这里是同一建筑的两个视图。我拍了照。我动了一下，然后我拿了
Here two views of the same building. I took picture. I moved a little bit and then I took
另外一张照片。所以我们可以看到观点完全不同。我们可以看到
another picture. So we can see that the view point is quite different. We can see that
这里堆积的烟囱是不同的，我们可以看到其中的烟叶少得多
the chimney stacked up here is different and we can see there’s far less foliage in one
图片的一面。所以，让我们说我对某一点很感兴趣
side of the picture. So let's say that I'm interested in a point
在这里，阳台的角落，在这个图像中，我可以找到它的像素坐标。我想要
here, the corner of the balcony and in this image I can find its pixel coordinate. I want
在另一个图像中找到相同的阳台。这对你和我很容易找到
to find that same balcony in the other image. That's very easy for you and me to find that
同样的点，我可以非常轻松地点击它，我这样做，我发现这里是它的
same point and I can click on it very very easily and I do that and I find here is its
像素坐标。所以两个不同的观点，世界上的同一点，同一个角落
pixel coordinate. So two different views, the same point in the world, the same corner
因为我移动了相机，所以它的像素坐标非常不同。
of the balcony when it's got to very different pixel coordinates because I moved the camera.
能够解决这种对应问题是许多机器人视觉算法的基础。
Being able to solve this correspondence problem is fundamental to many robotic vision algorithms.
我们不打算在本课程中介绍这些算法，但我认为这很有趣
And we're not going to cover those algorithms in this course, but I think it's interesting
只是概述了点检测器的原理并确定了对应关系。怎么可能
just to outline the principles of point detectors and determining correspondence. So how might
我们去解决这个对应问题？
we go about solving this correspondence problem?
如果我看一下阳台角落这个特定点的灰度值，
If I look at the grey scale value at this particular point on the corner of the balcony,
我发现它的灰度值为51.这很有趣。所以我也许那样
I find that it's got a grey scale value of 51. That's interesting. So I perhaps that
我去寻找另一个图像中具有51值的所有像素
I go and look for all the pixels in the other image that have got the value of 51. One of
他们可能在阳台的角落或其中一个可能是，但有很多
them might be on the corner of the balcony or one of them might be, but there are a lot
第二个图像中其他像素的值为51.实际上只是
of other pixels within that second image that have got a value of 51. In fact there's just
超过6,000个，它们在这里表示为黑色背景下的白点。
over 6,000 of them and they are indicated here as white dots against our black background.
很明显，这不是一个非常有用或可靠的技术。
So clearly this is not a very useful or reliable technique.
另一个困难是虽然像素
Another difficulty is that although the pixel
当我拍摄第一张照片时，其值为51，但是当我拍摄第二张照片时，该像素
had a value of 51 when I took the first picture, but when I took the second picture, that pixel
灰度值为47.因此寻找值为51的像素是荒谬的
has got grey scale value of 47. So looking for a pixel with a value of 51 is forlorn
因为我感兴趣的像素实际上有一个不同的灰度值，即使
because the pixel I'm interested in has actually got a different grey scale value even though
这是图像中的相同点。原因是曝光设置在
it's the same point in the image. The reason for that is that the exposure setting on the
相机可能略有不同。第二张图片有更多蓝天，曝光
camera is perhaps slightly different. The second image there is more blue sky, exposure
相机的数量不同，因此所有像素值都有一点变化。
of the camera is different and therefore all the pixel values have changed a little bit.
因此仅仅考虑灰度值是不够的。
So looking at the grey scale values alone is not enough.
我们需要考虑的另一点是，不可能总是找到一个
Another point that we need to take into consideration is that it's not possible to always find a
对应点。我们现在拍摄一个在天空中的像素。现在有很多
corresponding point. Let's now take a pixel that's in a sky. Now there is a whole lot
天空中的其他像素看起来与第一张图像中的天空像素完全相同。
of other pixels in the sky that look exactly the same as that sky pixel in the first image.
所以我们可以看到有些像素没有对应的点。
So we can see that there is some pixels for which there is no corresponding point.
我们可以从这个例子中学到一些关于尝试匹配天空中的像素的示例
We can learn something from this example about trying to match a pixel in the sky from one
框架到另一个。但是让我们放大这个特定的例子。每个灰色矩形
frame to the other. But let's zoom in on this particular example. Each of the grey rectangles
代表一个像素。我们将考虑中心3x3像素区域。
represents a single pixel. And we're going to consider a central 3x3 region of pixels.
所有这些像素都具有完全相同的值。这就是为什么他们被展示出来的原因
All these pixels have got exactly the same value. That's why they are shown with the
相同的灰色阴影。我要砍掉这个中央3x3区域，我要去了
identical shade of grey. I am going to chop out this central 3x3 region and I'm going
将它与一大堆相邻的3x3区域进行比较，您可以看到它们是
to compare it to a whole bunch of neighbouring\h3x3 regions and you can see that they are the
相同。
same.
无论我把这个移动的红色矩形放在哪里，它看起来与原始的完全相同
Wherever I put this moving red rectangles, it looks exactly the same as the original
3x3窗口。因此，我切出的这个中央窗口类似于其他八个可能的窗口
3x3 window. So this central\hwindow that I chopped out is similar to eight other possible
我可以放置3x3窗口的位置。它不是唯一的，这是问题所在
locations that I can put my 3x3 window. It's not unique and this is the problem with the
天空。所有像素都是相同的颜色。无论我放置3x3窗口，它看起来都一样
sky. All the pixels are the same color. Wherever I put the 3x3 window it looks the same as
中央3x3窗口。
the central 3x3 window.
让我们现在考虑一个边缘的例子。所以我们有一些浅灰色像素和一些
Let's consider an example now along an edge. So we have some light grey pixels and some
深灰色像素。我要完全做同样的事情。我要砍掉了
dark grey pixels. I'm going to do exactly the same thing. I'm going to chop out the
中间区域，然后我将它与一堆相邻区域进行比较
middle region and I'm going to compare it then to a bunch of neighbouring\hregions and
匹配那里不匹配，那里不匹配，不匹配，匹配
that matches\hthere doesn't match there, doesn't match there, doesn't match there, matches
好在这里，在这里不匹配。所以这个中央窗口在其他两个位置匹配。
well here and doesn't match here. So this central window matches at two other locations.
所以它更独特一点。
So it is a bit more unique.
现在考虑这种模式。单个暗像素与较亮像素的背景。我
Consider now this pattern. A single dark pixel against a background of brighter pixels. I'm
要切断中央区域，我将再次移动3x3窗口。
going to chop out the central region and once again I'm going to move the 3x3 window around.
我们发现它与其他任何地方都不匹配。它是独一无二的。它只与那匹配
And we see that it doesn't match anywhere else. It is unique. It only matches to that
中心位置。所以我们说这个特殊的3x3像素图案是本地唯一的。它的
central location. So we say that this particular 3x3 pattern of pixels is locally unique. It's
不同。这意味着它将成为我们可能认识到的模式
distinct. It's means that it's going to be a pattern that we could perhaps recognize
在一个不同的形象。
in a different image.
让我们试着将其形式化。我们将看看我们的中央3x3窗口。我们
Let's try\hto formalize this. We're going to look at our central 3x3\hwindow. We're
去看看从中央窗口移开的任意3x3窗口
going to look at an\harbitrary 3x3 window which is displaced from that central window
在水平方向上由ΔU组成，在垂直方向上由ΔV组成。所以我们
in the horizontal direction by delta U and in the vertical direction by delta V. So we
可以描述这两个窗口的相似性。资本I是我们的输入图像。参考资料
can describe the similarity of these two windows. Capital I is our input image. The reference
3x3窗口以坐标U，V为中心。要做到这一点，我们将索引我和
3x3 window is centred at the coordinate U,V. And to do that we are going to index I and
J在一个地区，所以我和J.在这个简单的例子中，它将在-1之间变化
J over a region, so I and J. In this simple example are going to vary between minus 1
加1。
and plus 1.
所以这是一个相似性度量。它会告诉我们中央窗口有多相似
So this is a similarity measure. It's going to tell us how similar the central window
是移动的窗口。我们可以计算任意有价值的转变的相似性。
is to the shifted window. We can compute the similarity for an arbitrary valuable shift.
如果两个区域相同并且具有较大的相似性，则相似性的值为零
Similarity's got the value of zero if the two regions are identical and has a large
如果区域不相似则为正值。现在我们将介绍一种衡量标准，即资本C
positive value if the regions are not similar. Now we'll introduce a measure, capital C which
我们称之为角落。
we call cornerness.
它与特定像素片段的唯一性有关。它是最小值
It's related to the uniqueness of a particular patch of pixels. And it is the minimum value
我们在参考窗口周围移动3x3窗口时的相似性。如果参考
of the similarity as we shift that 3x3 window around the reference window. If the reference
窗口类似于所有移位位置的窗口，然后是最小值
window is similar to the window in all the shifted locations, then the minimum value
相似性将是一个非常低的价值。我们的价值很低
of the similarity is going to be a very low value. We're going to have a low value of
cornerness;低独特性。所以这是一个不太明显的观点。
cornerness; a low value of uniqueness. So this is a point that's not very distinct.
但是，如果我们发现当我们移动窗口时，它与参考非常不同
If however we find that when we shift the window, it's very very dissimilar to the reference
窗口，那么相似度值都将非常高。最低限度
window, then the similarity values are all going to be very high. The minimum of all
这些非常高的价值将是更高的价值。所以我们将会有很高的价值
these very high values is going to be a higher value. So we're going to have a high value
角度或独特性的高价值。
of cornerness or a high value of uniqueness.
所以这是一个非常简单的角点检测器的下划线原则。一种叫做的探测器
So this is the underlined principle of a very simple corner detector. A detector known as
Moravec角落探测器，真正是各种现代角落的祖先
the Moravec corner detector and is really the ancestor of all sorts of modern corner
探测器跟随它的脚步。
detectors that have followed in it's footsteps.
现在我们可以概括这种方法。我们从以前得到了相似性度量。但现在
Now we can generalize this approach. We got our similarity measure from before. But now
我们要做的是引入高斯加权矩阵。它就在这里W.那是怎么回事
what we're going to do is to introduce a Gaussian\hweighting matrix. It’s here W. And what that's going
要做的是增加相对于靠近参考的窗户的重量
to do is to increase the weight with respect to windows that are close to the reference
窗口和减重测试窗口，远离参考窗口。
window and de-weight test windows that are further away from the reference window.
我们在这里通过一些数学工作，我们可以重写这个表达式
We're going worked through a little bit of maths here, we can rewrite this expression
就deltadelta和deltaV的向量而言，它是窗口偏移，乘以
in terms of a vector of delta U and delta V, which is the window shift, multiplied by
方阵A.这个矩阵A被称为结构张量，2x2矩阵和
a square matrix A. This matrix A is referred to as the structure\htensor,\h2x2 matrix and
它由图像渐变组成。所以我们谈谈如何计算图像渐变
it's comprised of the image gradiants. So we talk about how to compute image gradiants
之前。IU是水平梯度。IV是垂直梯度。G是高斯
before. IU is the horizontal gradient. IV is the vertical gradient. And G is a Gaussian
平滑的角落。
smoothing\hcorner.
这种结构张量的优点在于它基于图像梯度。所以任何
The advantage of this structure tensor is that it's based on image gradients. So any
由于相机曝光变化，太阳从后面出来的图像之间的差异
difference between images due to camera exposure change, the sun coming out from behind the
云。被强度梯度算子消除。
cloud. Is eliminated by the intensity gradient operator.
图像张量是2x2矩阵，因此它有两个特征值。特征值
The image tensor is the 2x2 matrix and so it's got two\heigenvalues. The\heigenvalues
在这个矩阵中告诉我们很多关于图像的特定部分。如果两个特征值
in this matrix tell us a lot about that particular part of the image. If both the eigenvalues
很小，然后它说图像的特定部分几乎是不变的。如果
are small, then it's saying that that particular part of the image is almost constant. If the
两个特征值都很小，那么图像的那部分几乎是不变的。它的
two eigenvalues are both small, then that part of the image is almost constant. It's
就像我们正在看的天空一样。该社区的所有像素都有
like the sky that we were looking at. All of the pixels in that neighbourhood have got
一个非常相似的价值。
a very similar value.
如果任一特征值很大但不是两者都是，则这对应于一个点
If either of the eigenvalues are large but not both then this corresponds to a point
它沿着图像的边缘排列。它没有告诉我们的方向
which is lined along an edge in the image. It doesn't tell us about the orientation of
边缘，它只是说图像的这个区域包含边缘。现在，如果两者
the edge, it's just says that this region of the image contains an edge. Now if both
特征值很大，那么这对应于一个峰值。它说我们有一个局部最大值
the eigenvalues are large, then this corresponds to a peak. It says that we have a local maxima
或者相对于周围的像素强度的最小值，因此这是非常独特的
or minima in pixel intensities with respect to the surrounds and so this is a very distinctive
我们能够在另一张图片中识别出来。
point that we're able to recognize in another image.
基于这个原理有几种算法确定是否有一个点
There were a couple of algorithms based on this principle which determine whether a point
在图像中很有趣，这通常被称为角落侦探，但更多
in the image is interesting and this is referred to often as corner detectives but that's more
适当地称为利益运营商。一个非常着名的是Shi-Tomasi探测器
appropriately referred to as interest operators. A very famous one is the Shi-Tomasi detector
它所做的只是为每个像素计算结构张量并采取
and what it does is simply for every pixel compute the structure tensor and take the
两个特征值中的最小值。如果两个特征值都很大，则Shi-Tomasi检测器具有
minimum of the two eigenvalues. If both eigenvalues are large, then the Shi-Tomasi detector has
很大的价值。
a large value.
另一个非常着名的是Harris角点探测器，它在原理上是相似的。它
Another very famous one is the Harris corner detector and it is similar in principle. It
有效地确定了具有两个大的特征值的像素，但是这样做了
effectively determines pixels that have got two large\heigenvalues\hbut it does it by
计算矩阵的行列式和矩阵的轨迹是两件事
computing the determinant of the matrix and the trace of the matrix which are two things
这非常容易计算，并且在这些和回报之间取得了比例差异
that are very very easy to compute and takes the scaled difference between those and returns
如果图像的特定部分很有趣，则该值很高。
the value that is high if that particular part of the image is interesting.
以下是Harris角落操作员输出的示例。积极的像素
Here is an example of the output of the Harris corner operator. Pixels that have got a positive
值以蓝色显示。具有负值的像素以红色显示
value are shown in blue. Pixels that have got a negative value are shown in red and
大约为零的像素显示为白色。输入图像的相应区域
pixels that are around zero are shown as white. The corresponding region of the input image
在右边显示在这里。
is shown over here on the right.
我们看到Harris探测器在有特色时会给​​出强烈的正值
We see that the Harris detector gives a strong positive value when there is a distinctive
图像的局部区域。我们可以在另一张图片中找到的东西。它
local region of the image. Something that we may be able to find in another image. It
对输入图像中的边缘给出强烈的否定响应。所以，如果我们在寻找
gives a strong negative response to an edge in the input image. So if we were looking
对于要尝试在另一个图像中定位的点，我们会寻找那些区域
for points to try and locate in another image, we would look for those regions where the
哈里斯角落值具有最强的正值。
Harris corner value had the strongest positive value.
现在我们在左图中找到了一些有趣点的坐标
Now that we found the coordinates of some interesting points in both the left image
和正确的图像，我们现在需要确定对应关系，哪个有趣点
and the right image, we now need to determine the correspondence, which interesting point
在第一图像中对应于第二图像中的哪个有趣点。而且，我们已经谈过了
in the first image corresponds to which interesting point in the second image. And, we have talked
在像素值本身如何不够独特之前。
before how the pixel values themselves are not sufficiently unique.
注意我在这里使用的符号，前导数字，1或2，表示哪个
Note the notation that I’m using here, a leading digit, the 1 or the 2, indicates which
我们正在讨论的特殊框架。所以，这表示第一张图片和这张图片
particular frame we are talking about. So, this indicates the first image and this one
表示第二张图像。解决个人非独特性的问题
indicates the second image. To get around the problem of the non-uniqueness of individual
在图像中的像素值，我们将看到以W为中心的W窗口
pixel values across images, we are going to look at W by W window of pixels centred around
每个角点。这些是具有W平方值的像素组
each corner point. These are group of pixels with W squared values
在它中可能比以兴趣点为中心的单个像素更加独特。
in it is likely to be much more unique than a single pixel centred at the interest point.
那么我们要做的是计算这个感兴趣的像素窗口
What we’re going to do then is to compute this window of pixels around the interest
在第一个图像中指向第二个图像中的所有兴趣点。
points in the first image and around all the interest points in the second image.
我们之前讨论了图像相似性度量，我们将再次使用它们
We talked previously about image similarity measures and we are going to use them again
这里比较这些以兴趣点为中心的窗口。让我们简要回顾一下
here to compare these windows centred on the interest points. Let’s recap very briefly
关于这些功能的实用性，特别是我们刚刚拥有的Harris角落功能
on the utility of these features, in particular the Harris corner feature that we have just
一直在描述。它导致对图像的非常简洁的描述。而不是图像
been describing. It leads to a very concise description of an image. Instead of an image
拥有数百万像素，我们现在有数百个功能。该功能是一个独特的
with millions of pixels in it, we now have hundreds of features. The feature is a distinct
点在场景中。这是我们可以从一个帧到另一个帧找到的东西，只是
point within the scene. It’s something we can find from one frame to the next, just
如果相机正在移动有用。我们现在只有数百个这样的功能而不是
useful if that camera is moving. We only have hundreds of these features now instead of
数百万像素。因此，Harris算法告诉我们每个算法的坐标
millions of pixels. So, the Harris algorithm tells us the coordinates of each of these
图像中的不同特征。现在，我们需要描述这些功能和
distinct features within the image. Now, we need to describe those features and
我们使用每个特征周围的W×W窗口来实现这一点，我们使用图像
we do that with a W by W window of pixels around each of those features and we use image
相似性度量来跨帧比较它们。另一种思考方式
similarity measures to compare them across frames. Another way of thinking about this
我们是否从图像中消除了许多不相关或无用的信息
is we have eliminated a lot of the irrelevant or not useful information from the image and
只关注图像中非常高价值的信息。
concentrated just on the very high value information within the image.
这种寻找角落特征并跨帧匹配的技术确实如此
This technique of finding corner features and matching them across frames is really
正如我们刚才所示，对于实时跟踪非常有用。
useful for real time tracking as we just showed.